JAMES RUTLEDGE

PHONE +1 512 423 8906 GITHUB github.com/jmz527

EMAIL jarutledge2@gmail.com

PERSONAL jamesaaronrutledge.com

LINKEDIN github.com/jmz527

LINKEDIN linkedin.com/in/jmz527

SUMMARY

I am an unflappable full-stack web developer with over five years experience. Homegrown steady diligence and raw passion define me. I thrive on complexity, revel a challenge, and I keep a reservoir of patience as auxiliary (for when debugging becomes an ordeal). If you are looking for a composed code-smith with an acute eye, a creative mind, and a collaborative spirit – then take note!

EXPERIENCE

September 2015 – Present

ENERGY METRICS

Software Developer | New York, NY

- Led the front-end development for Aligned Data Center's enterprise software solution.
- Implemented dozens of JavaScript & jQuery libraries, including extensive work with Highcharts.
- Collaborated with back-end developers to seamlessly integrate ASP.NET MVC with client side interface.
- Gave presentations on CSS frameworks and templating engines.
- Became deeply familiar with Twitter Bootstrap.

April 2015 – July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Full-Stack Web Development Student | Austin, TX

- 13 week full-time intensive course on full-stack web development.
- Studied programming fundamentals, responsive design, objectoriented programming, product development, & agile workflow.
- Led a group in building a review app using Ruby on Rails & PostgreSQL, resolved conflicts.

October 2010 – January 2013

MIND WINK

Co-Founder/Junior Web Developer | Austin, TX

- Designed & built websites/apps using Drupal, Wordpress, Bootstrap frameworks, gained an in-depth understanding of frontend development practices.
- Led pitch-meetings, developed presentations, established agile project management system & managed projects.
- Established cross-promotional campaigns with local businesses.
- Worked closely with clients to develop company brands.

January 2008 – September 2015

FREELANCE

Web Developer | Austin, TX

- <u>TurnPlot</u>, a social platform, virtual grid, and digital space to cultivate personal brands. Built using RubyOnRails & PostgreSQL.
- <u>PiqMapper</u>, a social analytics app allowing users to track their well being, over time, using colors. Built with NodeJS & MongoDB.
- <u>EcoRise Youth Innovations</u>: Worked closely with founder to develop & maintain PHP website. Pro bono.
- The Hub Cyclery: WordPress installation with a custom theme. Designed, built & maintained.

EDUCATION

Graduated July 2015

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Web Development Immersive | Austin, TX

Graduated August 2014

University of Texas

B.A. English, Minor in Film | Austin, TX

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, SASS, JSON, XML, Bash

Frameworks + Libraries

Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, jQuery, AJAX, Twitter Bootstrap, Highcharts, React, BackboneJS, Sinatra, Wordpress, Drupal, D3

METHODOLOGIES

Agile Development, MVC Design Patterns, Responsive Design, Object-Oriented Programming, Search Engine Optimization, Test-Driven Development

OTHER TOOLS

Git, GitHub, Heroku, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Grunt, Gulp, Bower, cPanel, Chrome DevTools, Adobe Creative Suite, MailChimp, QuickBooks

INTERESTS

- Web Development
- Filmmaking
- Travel
- Literature
- Art
- Cooking

FUN FACTS

- I was once hospitalized in Thailand I ate the street food (and it was worth it).
- One time I watched all three Lord of the Rings films back-to-back...the extended editions.
- In addition to Thailand, I have been to Japan, S. Korea, Spain, Italy, Greece, Turkey, Switzerland, Mexico and all throughout the Caribbean.
- I took two years of Chinese while in college.
- My favorite fruit is the mangosteen.
- I can juggle.